<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Caio Miguel</title>
    <link>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Caio Miguel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 16:00:52 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>O que está na taxa de mortalidade?</title>
      <link>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/whats-cfr-pt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 16:00:52 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/whats-cfr-pt/</guid>
      <description>Esse tópico vem me confundindo desde o início da pandemia do COVID-19. Deixe-me começar dizendo que estou fora do meu elemento aqui. Eu definitivamente não sou um epidemiologista. Às vezes nem sei se sou economista. Mas vamos lá.
Temos visto estimativas da taxa de mortalidade em torno de 3%. Esse número é calculado usando o total de mortes causadas pelo vírus dividido pelo total de infectados. É assim que a Enciclopædia Britannica define a CFR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s in a CFR</title>
      <link>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/whats-cfr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 16:00:52 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/whats-cfr/</guid>
      <description>This is a topic that has been confusing me since the coronavirus pandemic started. Let me start by saying I&amp;rsquo;m definitely out of my element here. I&amp;rsquo;m no epidemiologist. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure I&amp;rsquo;m an economist. But let&amp;rsquo;s get to it.
The case fatality rate has been quoted in the media and by experts as somewhere around 3%. This is calculated dividing the number of deaths caused by the virus by the number of cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazooka Blasts (what is QE?)</title>
      <link>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/qe-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 13:34:41 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/qe-works/</guid>
      <description>This topic is definitely a favorite of mine. And today is an exciting day for quantitative easing, so lets get into a short explanation of what it is.
Quantitative easing is a monetary policy tool that involves a central bank going directly to secondary markets and making financial asset purchases. Today, the Fed announced an unlimited quantitative easing program, in which it will purchase treasury securities, corporate and residential mortgage backed securities and, in a twist to some (although I have been saying they would do this since earlier this month), the Fed will purchase bond market ETFs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>   Swaps for Dummies (tentativamente traduzido)</title>
      <link>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/usd-swaps-pt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/usd-swaps-pt/</guid>
      <description>Além de ser uma palavra divertida de pronunciar, um swap (instrumento financeiro) é muito útil em períodos de escassez monetária como estamos vivendo hoje. Mas o que são os swaps e como chegamos a esse ponto?
Entendo que parece bobagem pensar que o mundo está no meio de um período de escassez monetária. As taxas de juros tem caído por boa parte dos últimos 50 anos nos países desenvolvidos e até mesmo no Brasil nos últimos anos, e bancos centrais ao redor do mundo têm expandido suas bases monetárias e comprado dívidas soberanas, produtos estruturados e até mesmo ações.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swaps for Dummies</title>
      <link>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/usd-swaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/blog/usd-swaps/</guid>
      <description>Besides being a fun word to pronounce slowly, a swap (financial instrument) is very helpful in times of currency shortage like today. But how did we get here and what do swaps do, exactly?
I know it sounds silly to think that the world is now facing a currency shortage. After all, interest rates have been trending down for around 50 years now and in the last decade alone we watched as central banks printed the world out of apparent certain doom by buying sovereign debt, asset backed securities, and straight out equities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Under new management. Click here to go back. Em construção. Clique aqui para voltar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff</title>
      <link>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caioaugustomiguel.github.io/stuff/</guid>
      <description>Under new management. Click here to go back Em construção. Clique aqui para voltar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>